cornys-moneypage.blogspot.com 2010-11-14

# Advertising and Privacy – Google Privacy Center

## Advertising and Privacy

(See our Privacy Policy for Google ads as well as the [DoubleClick Privacy Policy](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/).) 

Google offers a range of advertising services through our [AdWords](http://adwords.google.com/) and [AdSense](https://www.google.com/adsense/?hl=en) programs to show you the most useful and relevant ads online. These ads appear on Google’s sites and services, and on partner websites in the [Google Display Network](http://adwords.google.com/support/aw/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=6104). Some ads are based primarily on your search queries or on the content of the page you’re viewing. When providing ads tailored to your interests, we offer useful tools for you to view and manage the information that is being collected and used to serve ads. To protect your privacy, we follow three principles when we serve ads: 

  * **Transparency** – We provide detailed information about our advertising policies and practices. 
  * **Choice** – We offer innovative ways to view, manage and opt out of advertising cookies. 
  * **No personally identifying information** – We don’t collect or serve ads based on personally identifying information without your permission. 

The Google Privacy Policy describes how we treat personal information in Google’s products and services, including information provided when using or interacting with our advertising services. In addition, the Privacy Policy for Google ads and the Google Display Network and the specific privacy notices for Google services describe our privacy practices relating to our advertising services. Google also offers display advertising services through DoubleClick. For more information, see our [privacy practices related to DoubleClick](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/) advertising products. And to learn more about YouTube’s approach to advertising, see [YouTube Advertising and You](http://www.youtube.com/t/interest_based_ads). 

### Advertising Cookie Opt-out

Google uses cookies to improve your online experience, including the display of more relevant ads. Learn more about how Google uses advertising cookies. 

Anyone may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie (for AdSense partner sites, DoubleClick ad serving, and certain Google services using the DoubleClick cookie) at any time by clicking the button above. Google also offers a number of options to permanently save your opt-out settings in your browser. In addition, Google allows third party advertisers to serve ads on the Google Display Network. Using a tool created by the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/), you can [opt out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) of several third party ad servers’ and networks’ cookies simultaneously. (Google also uses cookies for Google Analytics and conversion tracking. Read more about this in our FAQ below.) 

Loading videos …

### Advertising Privacy FAQ

#### How does Google protect my privacy when it comes to advertising?

We make protecting privacy a priority by being clear about what information we collect and how we will use the information to show relevant ads, and by offering choices to consumers about what information to share with us. We also make it easy for you to view, manage and opt out of interest-based ads shown on AdSense partner sites and certain Google sites. We will not collect, sell, or share personally identifying information from ad serving cookies without your explicit consent. 

#### What information does Google use to serve me ads?

We serve ads on our own websites through our AdWords program, as well as on the [Google Display Network](http://adwords.google.com/support/aw/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=117120). We also serve ads on partner websites through our AdSense program. We use a variety of methods to deliver ads that are relevant. 

For our [AdWords](http://adwords.google.com/) program, we serve ads based on the subject matter of your search. For example, if you search for “golf” on our search engine, you’ll see golf-related ads. We also make ads geographically relevant, which we do with the help of IP addresses. If you’re in Boston searching for cab companies, you probably want ads for Boston-based, not London-based cabs. 

For the [Google Display Network](http://adwords.google.com/support/aw/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=117120), we serve ads based on the content of the site you view. For example, if you visit a gardening site, ads on that site may be related to gardening. In addition, we may serve ads based on your interests. As you browse websites that have partnered with us or Google sites using the DoubleClick cookie, such as YouTube, Google may place the DoubleClick cookie in your browser to understand the types of pages visited or content that you viewed. Based on this information, Google associates your browser with relevant interest categories and uses these categories to show interest-based ads. For example, if you frequently visit travel websites, Google may show more ads related to travel. Google can also use the types of pages that you have visited or content that you have viewed to infer your gender and the age category you belong to. For example, If the sites that you visit have a majority of female visitors (based on aggregated survey data on site visitation), we may associate your cookie with the female demographic category. 

In addition to ads based on interest categories, Google allows advertisers (including Google) to show you ads based on your previous interactions online, such as visits to advertisers’ websites. For example, someone who visited the website of an online sporting goods store can receive ads about special offers from that store. 

Google will not associate sensitive interest categories with your browser (such as those based on race, religion, sexual orientation, health, or sensitive financial categories), and will not use such categories when showing you interest-based ads. 

#### What information does YouTube use to serve me interest-based ads?

Using the DoubleClick cookie, [YouTube](http://www.youtube.com/) also displays interest-based advertising to show relevant ads on its site. The interest categories are determined by your visits to websites that use our AdSense program, as well as by the videos you prefer to watch or actions you take (such as uploading) on YouTube. The DoubleClick cookie associates your browser with relevant interest categories and uses these categories to show interest-based ads. We do not combine information from your YouTube account or Google account with the cookie data used to serve interest-based advertising. To learn more, see [YouTube Advertising and You](http://www.youtube.com/t/interest_based_ads). 

#### How do I edit my ads preferences for interest-based advertising?

Interest and demographic categories are based on visits to sites in the [Google Display Network](http://adwords.google.com/support/aw/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=117120). Using the Ads Preferences Manager, you can edit your ads preferences by adding interest categories that are relevant to you. You can also remove any interest categories that don’t apply and Google will no longer use them for showing you interest-based ads. You can change which demographic categories are associated with your browser. When you edit your ads preferences, your new settings may not take immediate effect, since it takes time for the change to be processed in our systems. 

#### How do I opt out of interest-based advertising?

If you prefer not to receive interest-based advertising, you can always click on the “Opt out” button at the top of this page, or click on the “Opt out” button on the Ads Preferences Manager. Google also offers a number of options to permanently save your opt-out settings in your browser. After you opt out, Google will not collect interest category information and you will not receive interest-based ads. You will still see the same number of ads as before, and Google may still show relevant ads based on the content of a web page, or other non-personal information. For example, if you visit a gardening site, Google can determine the content of the site and may automatically show ads related to gardening to all visitors without using a cookie. Additionally, whenever we serve an ad on Google search or on the sites of our AdSense for search partners, the ads which are displayed may still be based on the search terms you enter. 

#### How does Google use cookies to serve ads?

A cookie is a snippet of text that is sent from a website’s servers and stored on a web browser. Like most websites and search engines, Google uses cookies in order to provide a better user experience and to serve relevant ads. 

Google uses the DoubleClick cookie on AdSense partner sites and certain Google services to serve more relevant ads across the web and limit the number of times a given ad is shown to you. When you visit a website, view an ad, or click on an ad supported by Google’s advertising services, we may set a cookie on your browser. This advertising cookie will appear in your browser as coming from the domain “doubleclick.net.” 

When the cookie is set on your browser, it allows Google to gather information about your browser’s interaction with a given ad. This information gets recorded in a log that looks something like this: 

    time: 06/Aug/2008 12:01:32
    ad_placement_id: 105
    ad_id: 1003
    userid: 0000000000000001
    client_ip: 123.45.67.89
    referral_url: "http://youtube.com/categories"

The “time” field reflects the time the ad was displayed. The “ad placement id” and “ad id” identify the advertising campaign and the specific ad served. The “userid” is the display ad cookie that identifies the browser. The “client IP” reflects the user’s Internet Protocol (IP) address. A “referral URL” indicates the URL of the page where the ad was served. Our logs also record whether a user’s browser clicks on or interacts with an ad. 

This information helps Google deliver ads that are relevant to your interests, control the number of times you see a given ad, and measure the effectiveness of ad campaigns. Anyone who prefers not to see ads with this level of relevance can opt out of advertising cookies. This opt-out will be specific only to the browser that you are using when you click the “Opt out” button. 

#### How does Google use cookies for Google Analytics?

Google Analytics is Google’s free web analytics tool that helps website owners understand how their visitors engage with their website. Google Analytics collects information anonymously, and much like examining footprints in sand, it reports website trends without identifying individual visitors. Analytics uses its own cookie to track visitor interactions. The cookie is used to store information, such as what time the current visit occurred, whether the visitor has been to the site before, and what site referred the visitor to the web page. Google Analytics customers can view a variety of reports about how visitors interact with their website so they can improve their website and how people find it. A different cookie is used for each website, and visitors are not tracked across multiple sites. Analytics requires that all websites that use it must update their privacy policy to include a notice that fully discloses the use of Analytics. To disable this type of cookie, some browsers will indicate when a cookie is being sent and allow you to decline cookies on a case-by-case basis. In addition to declining cookies, you can also install the Google Analytics Opt-out Add-on in your browser, which prevents Google Analytics from collecting information about your website visits. 

Learn more about the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on and other Google Analytics privacy information.

#### How does Google use cookies for conversion tracking?

Google uses cookies to help businesses that buy ads from Google determine how many people who click on their ads end up purchasing their products. The conversion tracking cookie is set on your browser only when you click on an ad delivered by Google where the advertiser has opted-in to conversion tracking. These cookies expire within 30 days and do not contain information that can identify you personally. If this cookie has not yet expired when you visit certain pages of the advertiser’s website, Google and the advertiser will be able to tell that you clicked the ad and proceeded to that page. Each advertiser gets a different cookie, so no cookie can be tracked across advertiser websites. If you want to disable conversion tracking cookies, you can set your browser to block cookies from the googleadservices.com domain. 

#### What information does Google use to serve ads on Gmail?

Google scans the text of Gmail messages in order to filter spam and detect viruses. The Gmail filtering system also scans for keywords in users’ emails which are then used to match and serve ads. The whole process is automated and involves no humans matching ads to Gmail content. 

**For additional information about our advertising products and services, check out these FAQs:**

  * Analytics
